Finding aid for the R.B. Kitaj papers LSC.1741
UCLA Library Special Collections
- 12. Art Sources, 1939 - 2007; 35 boxes
  - Studio Materials
    - Partisan Review, Summer 1955 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Matisse (2 of 6), 2000 - 2007 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1998 - 2007 (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Announcements and invitations (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Pieter Bruegel: The dulle Griet in the Mayer van den Bergh museum, Antwerp, 1946 (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - "Tintoretto Beckett" (1 of 2), 1993 - 2002 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1993 - 2002 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1980 - 2002 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - "Photo Archive" (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - "Photo Archive", undated (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - "Photo Archive", undated (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - "Photo Archive", undated (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - "Photo Archive", undated (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - "Bacon" (1 of 3) (Box 146, Folder 9)
    - Frank Auerbach, 2001 - 2006 (Box 146, Folder 10)
    - Manuscript pages with biblical illustrations, undated (Box 146, Folder 11)
    - "God" (1 of 2), 1995 - 2005 (Box 146, Folder 17)
    - "Degas" (2 of 5), Undated. (Box 146, Folder 18)
    - "Supreme Court" (1 of 2) (Box 147, Folder 1)
    - "Minus" (3 of 3), 1985 - 2005 (Box 147, Folder 2)
    - "Nightbus" 2 of 2), 1984 (Box 147, Folder 3)
    - Tax Book (1 of 3), 1964 - 2002 (Box 147, Folder 4)
    - "Cities" (1 of 2), 1988 (Box 147, Folder 5)
    - "European Writers" (1 of 4) (Box 147, Folder 6)
    - "US Writers", 1992 - 2002 (Box 147, Folder 7)
    - "Orient" (1 of 2), 1978 - 1999 (Box 147, Folder 8)
    - Van Gogh (1 of 4), 1983 - 2006 (Box 147, Folder 9)
    - Van Gogh (2 of 4), 1990 - 2000 (Box 147, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 147, Folder 11)
    - "Photo Archive", Undated. (Box 147, Folder 12)
    - Matisse (3 of 6), undated (Box 147, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous (1 of 2), 1989 - 2006 (Box 147, Folder 14)
    - "J Matters" (2 of 6), 1963 - 2002 (Box 147, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 153, Folder 19)
    - "Orient" (2 of 2), 1978 - 1999 (Box 153, Folder 23)
    - Un-German Activities by Willibald Sauerlander, 1994 (Box 154, Folder 6)
    - Howard Hodgkin, 2002 - 2006 (Box 154, Folder 7)
    - Artforum, May 1967; 1 item. (Box 154, Folder 24)
    - L'Arte Moderna, 1967; 1 item. (Box 154, Folder 25)
    - I Maestri Del Colore: Vuillard (Number 170), 1 item. (Box 155, Folder 1)
    - The Masters 75: Bonnard -- fragments, 1967 - 1984 (Box 155, Folder 2)
    - Matisse (4 of 6), undated (Box 155, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1973 - 1995 (Box 155, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 155, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1965 (Box 155, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1939 - 1977 (Box 155, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1974 (Box 155, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1974 (Box 155, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 155, Folder 10)
    - "Photo Archive", Undated. (Box 155, Folder 11)
    - "Photo Archive", 1997 - 1999 (Box 155, Folder 12)
    - Manet/Chagall, 1980 (Box 155, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1995 - 2005 (Box 155, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 155, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous, 2005 (Box 155, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 1998 - 2004 (Box 155, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous, 1997 - 2005 (Box 155, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous, 1963 - 2003 (Box 155, Folder 19)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 155, Folder 20)
    - Matisse (5 of 6), 1990 - 2005 (Box 155, Folder 21)
    - Mounted image, undated (Box 155, Folder 22)
    - Miscellaneous, 1992 - 2006 (Box 155, Folder 23)
    - Miscellaneous, 2005 (Box 156, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 156, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 2006 (Box 156, Folder 3)
    - Klee, 2002 - 2006 (Box 156, Folder 4)
    - Hopper, 2004 - 2005 (Box 156, Folder 5)
    - Kandinsky, 2005 (Box 156, Folder 6)
    - Picasso (6 of 11) (Box 156, Folder 7)
    - Renoir, 2002 (Box 156, Folder 8)
    - Lautrec, 1991 - 2006 (Box 156, Folder 9)
    - Van Gogh (3 of 4), Undated. (Box 156, Folder 10)
    - "Not Fig" (1 of 3), 1977 - 1984 (Box 156, Folder 11)
    - "Not Fig" (2 of 3) (Box 156, Folder 12)
    - "Not Fig" (3 of 3), 1967 - 1976 (Box 156, Folder 13)
    - Publicity, 2000 - 2006 (Box 156, Folder 14)
    - Time Magazine cover -- proof, 1983 (Box 156, Folder 15)
    - Sandra / Two, 1996 (Box 156, Folder 16)
    - Love and Orthodoxy/ R.B. Kitaj and the man-woman story by Brendan Bernhard, May 2003 (Box 156, Folder 17)
    - Van Gogh/Gauguin (1 of 3), Undated. (Box 156, Folder 19)
    - Van Gogh/Gauguin (2 of 3), Undated. (Box 156, Folder 20)
    - "Bacon" (3 of 3), undated (Box 156, Folder 21)
    - "Rembrandt" (3 of 3), undated (Box 156, Folder 22)
    - Annotated articles (1 of 3) (Box 171, Folder 8)
    - Annotated articles (2 of 3), 1982 - 1988 (Box 171, Folder 9)
    - Annotated articles (3 of 3), 1982 - 1988 (Box 171, Folder 10)
    - Publicity, 1990 - 2002 (Box 171, Folder 11)
    - Annotated articles, 1990 - 2007 (Box 172, Folder 1)
    - Art ideas, sketches, notes (Box 172, Folder 2)
    - Art ideas, sketches, notes, 1967 - 1985 (Box 172, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous -- waterdamaged, 1984 - 2001 (Box 172, Folder 4)
    - Van Gogh (4 of 4), undated (Box 172, Folder 5)
    - Mounted photograph, undated (Box 172, Folder 6)
    - "Large Photos, etc" (1 of 4) (Box 172, Folder 7)
    - "Large Photos, etc" (2 of 4), 1978 - 1991 (Box 172, Folder 8)
    - "Large Photos, etc" (3 of 4), 1978 - 1991 (Box 172, Folder 9)
    - "Large Photos, etc" (4 of 4), 1978 - 1991 (Box 172, Folder 10)
    - "Mossad 2", 1990 - 2005 (Box 173, Folder 1)
    - "S" (2 of 2) (Box 173, Folder 2)
    - "J", 1983 - 2001 (Box 173, Folder 3)
    - "Clinton, FDR, etc.", 1997 - 2000 (Box 173, Folder 4)
    - "War", 1988 - 2000 (Box 173, Folder 5)
    - "History", 1995 - 2001 (Box 173, Folder 6)
    - "UK" (Box 173, Folder 7)
    - "Sport", 1996 (Box 173, Folder 8)
    - Tax Book (2 of 3), 1997 - 2000 (Box 174, Folder 1)
    - Tax Book (3 of 3), 1968 - 2002 (Box 174, Folder 2)
    - "Ins, subs, TV lic" (2 of 2), 1997 - 2003 (Box 174, Folder 3)
    - "Reading Tom Sawyer to Max" (3 of 3) (Box 174, Folder 4)
    - "Cities" (2 of 2), 1979 - 1999 (Box 174, Folder 5)
    - "Nightbus" (2 of 2), 1982 - 1985 (Box 174, Folder 6)
    - "Cafeist" (3 of 3), 1967 - 1984 (Box 174, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous articles -- various artists (1 of 2), 1990 - 2007 (Box 174, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous articles -- various artists (2 of 2) (Box 174, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1995 - 2004 (Box 175, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1981 - 2007 (Box 175, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous (1 of 2), 1996 - 2006 (Box 175, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous (2 of 2), 1996 - 2006 (Box 175, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 175, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 1987 - 2007 (Box 175, Folder 7)
    - Vincent, 1987 - 2007 (Box 176, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous articles -- various artists (1 of 2), 1993 - 2006 (Box 176, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous articles -- various artists (2 of 2), 1993 - 2006 (Box 176, Folder 3)
    - Angels/Angelology (Box 176, Folder 4)
    - "#1 Psycho, Gatsby, etc" (1 of 2), 1996 - 2005 (Box 176, Folder 5)
    - "#1 Psycho, Gatsby, etc" (2 of 2), 1996 - 2005 (Box 176, Folder 6)
    - Picasso (7 of 11), 1980 - 2002 (Box 176, Folder 7)
    - Picasso (8 of 11), 1994 - 1998 (Box 176, Folder 8)
    - Matisse/Picasso (Box 177, Folder 1)
    - Morandi, 2001 - 2006 (Box 177, Folder 2)
    - Titian, 1984 - 2003 (Box 177, Folder 3)
    - Hodgkin, 2004 - 2007 (Box 177, Folder 4)
    - Diebenkorn, Richard (2 of 2), 2003 (Box 177, Folder 5)
    - Mondrain (Box 177, Folder 6)
    - Michelangelo, 1993 - 2005 (Box 177, Folder 7)
    - Tintoretto Beckett (2 of 2), 1972 - 2005 (Box 177, Folder 8)
    - Bonnard (2 of 2), 1984 - 2005 (Box 177, Folder 9)
    - Vuillard, 1990 - 2003 (Box 177, Folder 10)
    - Matisse (6 of 6) (Box 178, Folder 1)
    - Picasso (9 of 11), 1985 - 2005 (Box 178, Folder 2)
    - Degas (3 of 5), 1981 - 2006 (Box 178, Folder 4)
    - Degas (4 of 5), 1981 - 2006 (Box 178, Folder 5)
    - Manet (2 of 3), 1966 - 2007 (Box 178, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous articles -- various artists (Box 178, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1994 - 2003 (Box 179, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous, 1995 - 2007 (Box 179, Folder 2)
    - Art ideas, sketches, notes, 1986 - 1996 (Box 179, Folder 3)
    - Film, 1999 - 2001 (Box 179, Folder 4)
    - Duchamp (Box 179, Folder 5)
    - Picasso (10 of 11), 1994 - 2004 (Box 179, Folder 6)
    - Euan Uglow, 1997 - 2007 (Box 179, Folder 7)
    - Philip Guston, 2003 - 2006 (Box 179, Folder 8)
    - Philip Guston -- catalogue photocopy (1 of 2), 1970 (Box 179, Folder 9)
    - Philip Guston -- catalogue photocopy (2 of 2) (Box 179, Folder 10)
    - Max Beckmann (2 of 2), 1964 - 2003 (Box 179, Folder 11)
    - "Giotto/Michelangelo" (1 of 2), 1960 - 2006 (Box 180, Folder 1)
    - "Giotto/Michelangelo" (2 of 2), 1991 - 2002 (Box 180, Folder 2)
    - Seascapes (1 of 2), 1977 - 1979 (Box 180, Folder 3)
    - Seascapes (2 of 2) (Box 180, Folder 4)
    - "34 Head Fiction/34 Heads, etc" (2 of 2), 1978 - 2002 (Box 180, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous, 1987 - 1994 (Box 180, Folder 6)
    - Borges, 2001 - 2004 (Box 181, Folder 1)
    - Joyce, 1999 - 2006 (Box 181, Folder 2)
    - Searle (Box 181, Folder 3)
    - Spinoza, 1990 - 2006 (Box 181, Folder 4)
    - "Shakespeare" (1 of 2), 1997 - 2004 (Box 181, Folder 5)
    - "Pound" (2 of 2), 1986 - 2005 (Box 181, Folder 6)
    - Beckett, 1996 - 2006 (Box 181, Folder 7)
    - Freud/Jung (Box 181, Folder 8)
    - "Giacometti" (2 of 2), 2002 - 2003 (Box 181, Folder 9)
    - "Rembrandt" (4 of 4), 1939 - 1960 (Box 181, Folder 10)
    - Anton Chekhov, 1981 - 2004 (Box 181, Folder 11)
    - Dostoevsky, 1968 - 2004 (Box 181, Folder 12)
    - "Painters" (3 of 3) (Box 182, Folder 1)
    - "Poets" (2 of 4), 1978 - 2005 (Box 182, Folder 2)
    - "Poets" (3 of 4), 1966 - 2006 (Box 182, Folder 3)
    - "Poets" (4 of 4), 1965 - 2007 (Box 182, Folder 4)
    - "Philosophers" (2 of 4), 1988 - 2006 (Box 182, Folder 5)
    - "Philosophers" (3 of 4) (Box 182, Folder 6)
    - "Philosophers" (4 of 4), 1981 - 2007 (Box 182, Folder 7)
    - "Art" (11 of 11), Undated. (Box 188, Folder 2)
    - "Amerika/Beisbol Boar Hunt/Kafka" (7 of 7), 1982 - 1990 (Box 188, Folder 3)
    - Van Gogh/Gauguin (3 of 3), 1996 - 2007 (Box 223, Folder 1)
    - Degas (5 of 5) (Box 223, Folder 2)
    - Manet (3 of 3), 1994 - 2004 (Box 223, Folder 3)
    - Matisse, Undated. (Box 223, Folder 4)
    - Munch ( 2 of 2), 2002 - 2006 (Box 223, Folder 5)
    - Picasso (11 of 11), 1991 - 2003 (Box 223, Folder 6)
    - "Art Ideas" (5 of 5) (Box 223, Folder 7)
    - Annotated articles, 1979 - 1996 (Box 224, Folder 2)
    - Annotated articles, 1967 - 2002 (Box 224, Folder 3)
    - Annotated articles, 2000 - 2006 (Box 224, Folder 4)
    - "Genizah" (2 of 2), 1992 - 1996 (Box 238, Folder 1)
    - "Revenge" (2 of 3) (Box 238, Folder 2)
    - "Revenge" (3 of 3), Undated. (Box 238, Folder 3)
- 13. Audio Visual Materials, 1980 - 2007; 3 boxes
  This series contains VHS tapes, compact discs, audio tapes regarding Kitaj's work.
  SERIES CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the reference desk in advance of your visit.
  - Cassette tape
    - "Marynka Smoking", 1987; 1 item. (Box 240, Folder 10)
    - "Sounds of the Sixties", undated; 1 item. (Box 240, Folder 11)
    - "R.B. Kitaj: A Retrospective", 15 February 1995 (Box 240, Folder 12)
    - "CCAC Commencement Speeches '95", 1995 (Box 240, Folder 13)
    - "Kitaj/Hockney", undated (Box 240, Folder 14)
    - "Desert Island Discs: Isaiah Berlin", undated (Box 240, Folder 15)
    - "Kaleidoscope", 7 November 1985 (Box 240, Folder 16)
    - Untitled (Box 240, Folder 17)
  - Compact disc
    - "Rhymes with Silver" music by Lou Harrison, 2000 (Box 240, Folder 18)
  - Videotapes
    - Kitaj Exhibition, Undated. (Box 240, Folder 1)
    - Kitaj in the Aura of Cezanne and Other Masters, Undated. (Box 240, Folder 2)
    - Kitaj in the Aura of Cezanne and Other Masters, Undated. (Box 240, Folder 3)
    - BBC: Stars and Mas, Undated. (Box 240, Folder 4)
    - Kitaj - Tape 1, 14 May 2004 (Box 240, Folder 5)
    - Kitaj - Tape 2, 14 May 2004 (Box 240, Folder 6)
    - Kitaj - Tape 3, 14 May 2004 (Box 240, Folder 7)
    - Kitaj - Tape 4, 14 May 2004 (Box 240, Folder 8)
    - Kitaj - Tape 5 (Box 240, Folder 9)